Finding Aid for Andrew W. Tanner Photographs 1894-1909
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- 8 x 10 Glass Plates
  - Michigan
    - Mackinac Island
      - Path/Road through woods, covered with leaves, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Path/Road through woods, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Winding path/road through woods, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Path/road through woods, tall trees alongside, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Path/Road through woods, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Path/Road along coastline with trees above, rocky shore, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Shore Drive, woods and beach, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Shore Drive, woods and beach, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Forked birch, path, and woods, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Two paths/roads diverging in woods, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Path/Road through woods, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Man and two women seated on rocks, circa 1900 (Box 14)
        (Grand Hotel in background)
    - Les Cheneaux
      - Fishing boat in water, approaching, coastline in foreground and distance, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Coastline and boat in water, approaching, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - View of islands from water, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Canoes lined in row at beach, island properties in distance, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Water with island properties in distance, one boathouse named "Islington" (?), circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - View of wooded islands, storm clouds looming, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - View looking out from one island, other islands on horizon, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Coastal buildings (silo, docks, businesses) at a distance, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - View of cottage and dock along water, circa 1900 (Box 14)
  - Unidentified Location
    - View looking up at ship in canal lock, people watching alongside canal, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - View looking up at ship in canal lock, people watching alongside canal, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Path through woods, tall trees alongside, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Beautiful building (a hotel?) with two stories, many columns and wide balconies; picket fence in foreground, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Two men standing in wooded area, in formal clothing; suitcase, canes, and hats on ground between them, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Two men in formal clothing, lying in grass, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Porch with chairs, rugs, and hammocks strung out, miscellaneous sports equipment, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Ship (Chippewa written onside), circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - View of houses along harbor, Mackinac Island?, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Houses (Box 14)
    - Building, boat and people alongside water (Box 14)
    - Building along water with dock (Box 14)
    - View of Francis Court, location unknown, circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Individuals in a car, California(?), circa 1900 (Box 14)
    - Airplane in an airfield runway, location unknown (Box 14)
  - Drawing of Fort Michilimackinac(?) Mackinac Island(?) (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous Series (1 linear foot) includes some biographical information, inventories of Tanner's photographs made by Jack Kausch, Tanner's film negatives, most of unknown locations and dates, copy negatives, diapositives, and prints made by Kausch from Tanner's negatives, and two videos featuring some of Tanner's photographs, both of which were created by Kausch. These videos, both short, provide an excellent visual introduction to Tanner's photographic work.
  - Biographical (Box 15)
  - Photo inventories (Box 15)
  - Prints
    - Colorado (Box 15)
    - Illinois (Box 15)
    - Kansas (Box 15)
    - Les Cheneaux Islands (Box 15)
    - Mackinac Island (Box 15)
    - Mexico (Box 15)
    - Mississippi River (Box 15)
    - Missouri (Box 15)
    - Texas (Box 15)
    - Unidentified (Box 15)
    - Mounted, unidentified (Box 15)
  - Diapositives, unidentified (Box 15)
  - Negatives
    - Summer 1896 (Box 15)
    - Les Cheneaux, 1894 (Box 15)
    - Mackinac Is, 1894 (Box 15)
    - Tanner family (Box 15)
    - Unidentified
      - 3 5/8" x 3 5/8" negatives (Box 15)
      - 3 5/8" x 5 7/8" negatives (Box 15)
      - Copy negatives and diapositives, 7 folders (Box 15)
      - 35 mm copy negatives (Box 15)
  - Videos
    - Andrew Wineland Tanner: A Sense of History. Photographs of the late 19th and Early 20th Century. (Box 15)
    - Les Cheneaux: En Bateaux, 1987 (Box 15)